#6: Face animation
#6: 脸部动画
Now our character can move. It's time to make him talk.
现在我们的角色能动了。是时候让它开口说话了。
In the "mimic" folder I have several head images.
在"mimic" 文件夹有几张头像。
Switching them at a certain frequency creates an illusion of a talking character.
按照一定的顺序切换它们能产生角色开口说话的错觉。
That's what we are going to do.
这就是我们要做的事。
Let's create a new file and quickly assemble our character. Just as we did before.
我们新建一个文件然后快速装配好角色。这和之前做的是一样的。
Now we need to import the head images.
现在我们需要导入那些头像。
Select the files with numbers from 1 to 5.
选择编号1到5的文件。
The sixth file we keep for later.
第6号文件先放着稍后再用。
Now let's group those heads together.
现在我们把所有头部都合到一个组中。
But for this case I will be using a special Switch Group instead of the regular one. Here.
不过这回稍微有点不同的是我要用一个特殊的切换组(Switch Group)来代替常规的组。这里。
The Switching group behaves just like an ordinary group...
切换组有点像普通的组...
...but it shows only one of its child layers at a time.
...不过它每次只显示一个子层。
This group have a special parameter called "Active Layer Name"...
这个组有个被称为“活动层名(Active Layer Name)”特别的参数...
...which defines the name of layer to display.
...其定义了要显示的层的名字。
Let's change it, to make our character close his mouth.
我们更改它，让角色合上嘴吧。
Press Enter. Done.
按下回车键。完成。
If we change this parameter in the Animation mode...
如果我们在动画模式中对这个参数做更改...
...the new waypoints will appear and the layers will be switching.
...新的航点出现，层开始切换。
Now let's put head inside of this group.
现在让我们把头放到这个组里。
Choose "Cut"...
选择“剪切(Cut)”...
Select this layer...
选择这个层...
...and "Paste".
...然后“粘贴(Paste)”。
Notice that new layers are always inserted right above of the selected one.
注意新层总是被插入到被选中的层之上的。
Now let's import audio file with a voice of our character.
现在我们导入带有角色声音的音频文件。
Choose "File" -> "Import"...
选择“文件(File)” > “导入(Import)”...
...and in the "mimic" folder select "sound.wav".
...在"mimic" 文件夹中选择 "sound.wav".
Let's listen to an audio track.
我们试听一下。
So, we've got two phrases.
好，有两句短句。
Let's mark the beginning and the end of each phrase with keyframes.
我们用关键帧标注每句短语的开始和结尾。
Done.
完成。
Now we're going to switch head images in this and that intervals.
现在我们要从这里到那里的声程间切换头像。
Turn the Animation mode on...
打开动画模式...
...go two frames ahead...
...向前两帧...
...and switch the first layer.
...切换第一个层.
Now further a bit more...
再多来一些...
and so on.
等等。
Right now I won't going to try to perfectly synchronize mouth shapes with voice.
此刻我不打算去完美同步口型和声音。
Instead, I will place them randomly - that should be enough for now.
反而，我随机的放置 - 应该就够了。
Let's check out the result.
我们看看结果。
Okay, he is talking now.
好啊，现在他开口说话。
In this example all our head images are of the same size, so we don't have any problems.
在这个例子中我们的全部头像都是用样尺寸的，所以我们没有碰到任何问题。
But suppose if we want to add an extra head image with a different dimensions.
但假设我们想要添加多一张不一样坐标的头像。
Import "head-extra" file...
导入 "head-extra" 文件...
And place it into the switch group.
并把它放到切换组中。
It's not visible for now. Let's switch in on at some moment.
现在还看不见。我们在某个时刻切换出来。
See? The guy's head jerks aside.
看到吗？这家伙的头抽风了一样。
That's because the image doesn't coincide with the others.
这是因为这张图像和其他不一致。
So we have to adjust it.
我们不得不调整调整。
But it's not that easy, because I can't see other heads at the same time!
但不是那么容易的，因为我不能同时看到其他头像！
So here we will use a Onionskin mode.
所以，在此我们要用洋葱皮模式。
When Onionskin is enabled we can see an image from the previous keyframe.
当洋葱皮模式打开后，我们能看到来此前一个关键帧的图像。
Now it's become easy to align the image.
现在对齐图像就变得容易多了。
Just don't forget to switch the Animation mode off before you start, or else nasty miracles would happen.
只是不要忘了在开始之前关掉动画模式，要不然讨厌的事情就会出现哦。
Select the head image... and adjust.
选择这张头像...进行调整
Done.
完成。
Now everything works as expected.
现在一起都如我们所愿了。